♪〜
I want to talk...
About your Wonderful Original
Interviews with Monster Girls
The class is astir
I want to let myself go too,
But I end up putting on a fake smile.
Your eyes alone conveyed a competitive spirit
Biting at your lip forcefully.
You once said,
"I wouldn't want to worry what someone thinks
And end up hurting someone else in the process!"
When the chime rings out, as the rain lifts up,
We'll pass the boundaries of our school!
Jumping through the puddles, light will scatter about
Our smiles, and wishes will be so bright!
I want to talk...
About your Wonderful Original!
〜♪
Takahashi Tetsuo Wants to Protect
Oh, her?
（井森(いもり)）
あいつか〜 あいつさ
She's...
ちょっと調子に乗ってない？
kinda arrogant, don't you think?
（雪(ゆき)）うっ…
I admit she is cute,
（井森）
かわいいのは認めるけどさ
but she could hang out with him once, at least.
遊びくらい
行ってやってもいいのに
Maybe she thinks she's some kind of idol...
（木村(きむら)）
アイドルにでも
なったつもりなのかね
ハア…
あっ
Biology Prep Room
（無音）
（雨が降っている音）
Kusakabe?
（高橋(たかはし)）日下部(くさかべ)？
（雪）はっ
たっ… 高橋先生
M-Mr. Takahashi...
What's wrong?
（高橋）どうした？
じ… 実は 自分が その
I-It's just... I heard people...
s-saying mean things... about me.
わっ… 悪く言われているのを
聞いてしまって
そうか
I see.
Well, this isn't the place to talk about it.
ここで話しててもなんだから
話は中で…
Let's go inside.
Is it because I'm a demi?!
（雪）私がデミだからですかね？
（高橋）えっ？
If I weren't a demi,
（雪）私がデミでなければ
こんな気持ちには…
I wouldn't feel like this...
（雪がすすり泣く声）
（高橋）
大丈夫だ それは違う
それは違うぞ 日下部
Don't worry. That's not true.
That isn't true, Kusakabe.
Mr. Takahashi...
（雪）高橋先生…
（雪がすすり泣く声）
（氷の粒が落ちた音）
（高橋）ん？
あっ…
I have to protect her.
（高橋）
守らねばなるまい
デミちゃんを守らねば
I have to protect this demi!
Generally speaking,
（高橋）
一般的にいえば 陰口など
女子高生にありがちな些細(ささい)な悩みだ
gossip is a trivial issue, common among high school girls.
But since she's a demi,
だが 彼女がデミである以上
this particular issue isn't quite that simple.
それは単純に
片づけられるものではないだろう
Hikari and Machi have accepted that, and are living normally enough...
ひかりや町(まち)なんかは
受け入れて生活してるからな
（早紀絵(さきえ)）あっ
（高橋）ん？
（高橋）あっ 佐藤(さとう)先生
Ms. Satou?
（高橋）アジサイですか？
Hydrangeas, eh?
（早紀絵）
庭に たくさん咲いていたので
せっかくですし
There were lots of them in the garden,
so I borrowed a few.
高橋先生は お仕事ですか？
Are you working, Mr. Takahashi?
（高橋）
ハハッ こんな天気で
薄暗い準備室に籠もってばかりだと
Yes, with the weather like this,
staying in that dark prep room is depressing.
気がめいりますからね
（早紀絵）
あの…
私 高橋先生を誤解してました
Um... I was wrong about you, Mr. Takahashi.
（高橋）え？
Huh?
The thing with Machi's backpack...
（早紀絵）
町さんのリュック通学の件
I happened to hear you asking the principal to help.
校長先生に お願いしていたのを
たまたま聞いてまして
Oh, that—
（高橋）ああ あれは…
（早紀絵）
高橋先生はデミに対して
優しい気遣いをするような方なのに
Even though you're someone so considerate of demis,
私ったら入学式の準備のときには
あんな態度をとってしまって
on the day of the opening ceremony, I behaved that way toward you!
I'm so sorry!
すみませんでした！
（高橋）
ああ いえ
あのときは自分のほうこそ
Oh, not at all!
I should be the one to apologize for being insensitive to your situation.
先生のご事情も考えず
無神経だったと
As for the backpack, Hikari...
それに リュックの件は ひかり…
Takanashi asked me to help.
小鳥遊(たかなし)から頼まれたんです
Takanashi? The older sister, you mean?
小鳥遊さん…
ってお姉さんのほうの？
Yeah.
（高橋）
ええ あの子たちと
身近に接していながら
I work so closely with those girls,
結局
何も気付いてやれてないんですよ
but I didn't notice anything.
もっと あの子たちのことを
理解したいと
I want to understand them better, but...
思ってはいるのですが…
Um, Mr. Takahashi?
（早紀絵）あの 先生
Yes?
（高橋）はい？
Um...
（早紀絵）
その… 私も協力させて
いただけませんでしょうか？
C-Can I be of any help at all?
（高橋）え？
Huh?
I'm a demi, after all!
私 デミですから！
ああ ええ それは もう
この身でしっかり…
Yes, I've experienced that firsthand.
ああっ…
I mean...
（早紀絵）
きょ… 教師でもありますし
A-And I'm also a teacher!
デミの生徒の悩みなら
I have a duty to address the concerns of my demi students!
私も 一緒にお手伝いする
義務というか
そういう意味も含めまして
協力できると！
With that in mind, I really think I can help!
ハア ハア ハア…
（早紀絵）
しまった！
Oops.
いや…
それは願ってもないことですよ
No, I think that sounds perfect...
I'd appreciate your help.
ぜひ お願いします
やった〜！　フフッ
All right!
（高橋）ハア〜
So, the students who said mean things about Kusakabe...
（高橋）
その 日下部を悪く言っていた
生徒なんですが
It seems they constantly gossip about others as well.
どうやら 常習的に
人の陰口を言っているようなんです
Then, Kusakabe wasn't being specifically targeted?
（早紀絵）
じゃあ 特に日下部さんに
限ったことではないんですね
Probably not.
（高橋）多分
But she's convinced that it's because she's a demi?
（早紀絵）
でも 彼女は
“自分がデミだから”と
思い込んでしまった
（高橋）うん
佐藤先生は どう思いますか？
What do you think, Ms. Satou?
Even without considering the gossip,
（早紀絵）
陰口のこと以前に 日下部さん
Kusakabe seems to avoid contact with other people, to begin with.
いつも 人との接触を
極力 避けてるように見えるんです
I mean, in a different way than I do.
その… 私とは違う意味で
（高橋）
確かに そんな感じはありますね
Yeah, I noticed that, too.
彼女には
何か事情があるのかもしれません
Maybe she has some reason.
A reason.
事情… 家庭的なこととか？
You mean something like her family?
I have a feeling it's more connected to her nature as a demi.
（早紀絵）
というより デミの性質に
由来するような気がするんです
Her nature?
性質ですか？
The reason I had the wrong idea about you
（早紀絵）
私が高橋先生を
誤解してしまったのも
サキュバスの性質のため
was because my succubus nature made me overly self-conscious.
自意識過剰に
なってしまったからですし
（高橋）なるほど そういう見方も
I see... There's that way of looking at it.
She probably doesn't have anyone to talk to about it,
（早紀絵）
恐らく
相談相手もいないでしょうし
なおさら デミとしての折り合いが
つけにくいのではないでしょうか
which makes it even harder to come to terms with her demi identity.
ハア〜 やっぱり
もっと早く声かけとくんだったな
I guess I should have tried to talk to her sooner...
Well, why don't I try to speak to her?
あの 私のほうから
聞いてみましょうか？
えっ？
Talking to another demi might be easier for her.
デミ同士なら
話しやすいでしょうし
That would be a big help.
それは助かります
I'm really glad you're on this with me.
佐藤先生がいてくれて
よかったですよ
ととと… とんでもないです！
N-N-N-Not at all! It's just what any teacher ought to do!
それくらい
教師としては当然ですので
日下部のフォローも
そうなんですが
Talking to Kusakabe is important...
えっ？
But we should also do something about the students who were gossiping.
陰口を言っていた
生徒たちのことも…
You're right.
そうですね
ただ言うなというだけでは…
Telling them to stop won't work.
They don't want people to know they feel inferior,
（高橋）劣等感をごまかしたい
かといって
面と向かって言うのは怖い
but they're afraid to face their victims.
I believe that mental weakness
陰口を言う心理は
is what makes people gossip about others.
そういった心の弱さから
来るものだと思います
If possible,
できれば 彼女たちに
I'd like them to realize that they don't have to rely on gossip.
陰口に逃げない心を
持ってほしいんです
Yes.
ええ
Maybe it would be unfair to expect that from high school students...
高校生に それを求めるのは
酷な話ですかね
Now, what to do?
（高橋）さて どうしたもんか
Takanashi, wait a minute.
（雪）
小鳥遊さん！
ちょっと待ってよ
（高橋）ん？
（雪）
ねえ どこに行くの？
ちょっと… 小鳥遊さん
Hey, where are we going?
Hey, Takanashi...
小鳥遊さん！
Takanashi!
ひかり
Hikari?
And they just left it like that.
（木村）そのままにしたんだって
No way! That's crazy!
（井森）それ ヤバいじゃん
（２人の笑い声）
Also, I heard the physics teacher, Iwai, is being sent to another school.
小鳥遊さん…
Takanashi...
（ひかり）
ユッキー
私 あいつらに文句言いに行くから
Yukki, I'm going to give them a piece of my mind.
Really? Why?
ユッキーは
ここで待って聞いてて
You wait here and listen.
It seems like he got involved in some risky stuff.
えっ…
What the hell?
I'll let you decide what happens afterward.
そのあと どうするかは
ユッキーに任せるから
With that face, maybe it can't be helped.
You think he went after someone?
No way. He wouldn't have the guts.
（木村）
んなことできないでしょ
ヘタレだし
（井森）かっこわる〜
（木村）ハハハッ
What a loser!
（２人）ん？
（木村）あんた 確か Ｂ組の…
Aren't you from class B?
（井森）ああ バンパイアの
（木村）小鳥遊…
Oh, the vampire.
Takanashi...
Is trashing people behind their backs all you ever do?
あんたたち
人の陰口ばっかり言ってるんでしょ
Give it a rest.
やめなよ そういうの
ああ？
Huh?
Oh, is this about Kusakabe?
あ〜 何？　日下部のこと？
（木村）ああ〜
As a fellow demi, you're out to avenge her?
同じデミだから弔い合戦ってわけ
かっこいい…
That's cool of—
No!
（ひかり）違う！
（２人）あっ…
Yes, Yukki is a demi, but it doesn't matter!
（ひかり）
確かにユッキーはデミだけど
関係ない！
あんたたちに文句を言うのは
I'm giving you two a piece of my mind
あんたたちに
文句を言いたいからよ
because that's what I want to do!
相手をあおって
はぐらかそうとするな！
Don't try to dodge it by provoking me!
If you don't want to stop blabbing about people, then fine...
別に陰口を言うのを
やめたくなかったら それでもいい
でも あんたたちが言ってるのを
見たり聞いたりしたら
But every time I see or hear you doing it,
I'll call you on it.
その度に 文句を言いに行くから
If you want to hang around and badmouth people,
のんびり他人(ひと)の悪口を言いたいなら
私の目や耳に入らない所でやって
you'd better do it where I can't find you.
あっ 先生…
Mr. Takahashi...
We aren't the only ones who talk about people behind their backs.
（木村）
別に陰口言ってるのって
私たちだけじゃねえじゃん
なんで私たちだけ文句…
Why single us out?
（ひかり）あんたたちだけじゃない
It won't be just you two.
陰口を言っている人を見聞きしたら
誰にだって 私は文句を言う
I'll give a piece of my mind to anyone I catch badmouthing someone else!
なんで そんなに躍起になるんだよ
Why are you so gung-ho about this?
陰口言うなんて
誰でもやってるだろ
Everyone talks about people behind their backs.
みんながやってるから
なんて理屈 私は嫌い！
I can't stand the excuse that "everyone does it"!
みんな
傷つけ合ってるから
Everyone hurts people,
私も傷つけていいなんて
so you think you're allowed to hurt people?
口にして
恥ずかしくないの？
Aren't you ashamed to say that?
No one in the world likes being badmouthed!
陰口を言われて
うれしい人なんているわけないのに
What, so you never talk about anyone behind their back?
（木村）
じゃあ なに
あんたは人の陰口言わないの？
（ひかり）
言わない 言いたいことがあれば
全部 直接言う
No. If I want to say something, I say it to their face.
言えなければ 言わない
If I can't, I say nothing.
（井森）
そうすれば
自分は陰口をたたかれないとでも？
You think that will keep people from talking about you?
No, I don't.
（ひかり）それはない
I know as soon as I leave,
だって 私がここを去ったあと
２人は私の陰口を言うでしょ？
you two will start griping about me.
（２人）あっ…
Sorry.
（ひかり）ごめん
（２人）ん？
（ひかり）
その 今の言い方は意地悪だった
It was mean of me to say it that way.
（井森）は？　えっ うん…
Huh? Er, s-sure...
（ひかり）
陰口を言わない人も
陰口を言われると思う
I know people who don't badmouth others still get badmouthed.
むしろ
言われやすいんじゃないかな？
In fact, they're probably the easiest targets.
（ひかり）でも 決めたんだ
（２人）うん？
But I've made up my mind!
It's just for my satisfaction, but...
ただの自己満足だけど
Even if people say mean things about me, I won't do anything I'll regret!
私は人から言われても
後ろめたさが残ることはしないって
はっ
あんた 泣いて…
Are you... crying?
Sorry, I've said what I wanted to say.
（ひかり）
ごめん
言いたいこと言ったから
I'll go now.
もう行くから
I can't agree with what you said,
（木村）
あんたが言ったこと
納得はできないけどさ
なんか すごいって思ったよ
but I am kinda impressed.
Still, why would you say all that?
でも どうして そこまで…
（ひかり）
約束したから
Because I promised...
妹と約束したから
I promised my sister.
Your sister?
（木村）妹？
（井森）小鳥遊ひま…
Takanashi Hima—
（２人）あっ
Ku...
（木村）くっ…
（井森）日下部
Kusakabe...
ごめんなさい
I'm sorry!
（２人）え？
I, um...
（雪）私 その…
実は 自分のデミの体質に
疑問があって
The truth is, my demi nature still bothers me,
それでちょっと
人と接するのを避けてて
so I've always avoided contact with people.
それが
不快に感じたようだったら
If that gave you a bad impression,
well... I'm sorry.
その… ごめんなさい
（木村）なんで あんたが謝るのよ
Why are you apologizing?
（井森）私たちこそ
We're the ones who should...
ごめん
Sorry.
うっ…
Wha—
（ひかり）なっ…
（高橋）上がってるぞ
The rain stopped.
ちょっ…
You—
You hungry? I'll treat you to something.
（高橋）
腹減ってないか？
何か飯でも おごってやろうか？
（ひかり）痛(い)たた…
Ow, ow, ow!
もう 髪結ったとこ なでたら痛い！
It hurts when you rub my head where my hair's tied up!
（高橋）すまん すまん
（ひかり）なでるなら後ろ！
Sorry about that.
If you're gonna rub it, rub the back!
I'm home.
（ひかり）ただいま〜
（ひまり）おかえり
Welcome back.
（ひかり）おっりゃ〜！
（ひまり）うわあ〜！
（ひかり）フフッ
（ひまり）は？
Huh?
Don't ask.
（ひかり）いいから
（ひまり）なっ… 何なのよ 急に
Wh-Where'd this come from?
Don't ask.
（ひかり）いいから
Did something happen at school?
（ひまり）学校で何かあった？
（ひかり）うん 大丈夫
No, I'm fine.
Interviews with Monster Girls
Audiovisual Room
The thing is, a student came to talk to me recently...
（高橋）
実は先日
とある生徒に相談されてだな
それについて
俺に思うところがあって
I had my own thoughts about it, so I called you all here.
みんなに集まってもらったわけだ
Ms. Satou, too.
佐藤先生にもな
（町）
えっ 相談？
私はしてませんが…
Someone talked to you? It wasn't me.
（ひかり）私でもないもん
Me, either.
（２人）あっ…
（高橋）お前ら 下手くそか
Can't you guys be more sensitive?
すっ すみません…
S-Sorry.
W-We couldn't help it! There's only three of us here!
しし… しかたないじゃん
もともと３択だし
（高橋のせきばらい）
フフッ
（高橋）とにかくだ
Anyway, I know there are many things demis might worry about now.
デミが いろいろと
悩みを抱えやすいことが分かった
お前たちには 互いに積極的に
I'd like for you three to be able to help each other out.
相談し合えるように
なってほしいと思っている
You three are the only demi students at this school.
この学校で
デミの生徒は３人だけだ
I'd like you to treasure that link among you.
そのつながりを大切にしてほしい
友達に聞きにくいことがあれば
俺や佐藤先生を頼ってくれ
If you can't confide in your friends, you can come to me or Ms. Satou.
In particular, Ms. Satou, is a demi, like you, as well as a woman.
特に佐藤先生は
みんなと同じデミであり女性だ
こんなに心強い方はいないぞ
There's no one you can trust more.
私も相談する側のほうが…
はっ！
I'd rather be the one seeking advice from—
ああっ…
私にも遠慮なく相談してね
F-Feel free to talk to me anytime, too!
（高橋）
言いたかったのは それだけだ
That's all I wanted to say.
実際に みんなで集まって
話したんだということで
I hope you're aware that getting together to discuss things like this is important.
大事なことなんだと
認識してもらえるとうれしい
Does anyone have anything they'd like to talk about right now?
取り急ぎ 何か相談したいことが
あるヤツはいるか？
まあ 急には思いつかんか
I guess you can't think of anything right now.
じゃあ 今日は この辺で…
That'll be all for today, then—
（ひかり）はい！
（高橋）ん？
Me!
私 まだ先生に
ハグしてもらってません
I haven't gotten a hug from you yet!
（高橋）は？
（早紀絵）ハグ？
Huh?
Hug?
（ひかり）おりゃ〜！
Hi-yah!
ぎゅう〜
Squeeze...
（ひかり）エヘヘッ
（高橋）アハハ 何？
Hee hee.
Ha ha... What?
（ひかり）エヘヘヘッ
（高橋）アハハハ だから何？
Hee hee hee!
Ha ha ha. Seriously, what?
（町）はっ！　私もいいですか？
（高橋）え？
C-Can I have one, too?
Huh?
Sure.
（高橋）はい
（町）わぷぷっ…
（町）ありがとうございます
（高橋）いえ…
Thank you.
No problem.
（ひかり）よかったね マッチー
（町）うん
Good for you, Macchi!
Yep.
（早紀絵）高橋先生
（高橋）は？
Mr. Takahashi...
ウフッ
I'll take one, too—
ついでに私も！
No, that's a bad idea...
（高橋）いや それは さすがに…
（早紀絵）そうですよね
You're right.
○Ｘ＄＃％□…
ああ どうだ？
日下部も よかったら…
Uh...
How about it, Kusakabe? If you'd like one, too...
While we're at it.
（高橋）流れで
（雪）えっ？
Huh?
（早紀絵）ええ〜！
（町･ひかり）流れ？
While you're at it?!
Kusakabe...
（高橋）日下部
無理に悩みを話せとは言わない
I won't force you to talk about what's troubling you.
Like I said before,
さっきも言ったとおり
I believe it's fate that you're in an environment
お前が ほかのデミたちに
囲まれた環境にあることは
きっと何かの縁だと思う
where you're surrounded by other demis.
だから うまく言えないが
きっと良くなる 必ず楽しくなる
So... I can't say it well, but I'm sure it'll get better.
You will have fun.
So don't worry.
だから 安心しろ なっ
Okay?
（雪）はい
Yes.
先生！　先生！
Mr. Takahashi, Mr. Takahashi!
この子にも
ハグしてあげてください
Give her a hug, too!
（高橋）
“この子”って それ 町だろ
Her? But that's Machi.
（ひかり）流れ 流れ
（高橋）まったく…
Just while you're at it!
Sheesh... Is that all right, Machi?
（高橋）いいのか？　町
（町）あっ はい
Uh, sure.
All right, then...
（高橋）よいしょっと
（警告音）
はあっ！
えっ じゃっ…
じゃ 今日は この辺で
Well, that'll be all for today.
（早紀絵）
高橋先生 今の奇声は 一体！
Mr. Takahashi, what was that weird scream?!
（雪）
一体 何があったんですか？
What happened?
Wait! I have a question!
（ひかり）
先生 待って 相談！
今のリアクションの
意味について 相談を…
I want to know what that reaction meant!
He called all the demis together for a meeting?
（ひまり）デミを集めて相談会？
（悠子(ゆうこ)）
うん 高橋先生が
放課後に視聴覚室で
Yeah, Mr. Takahashi had them meet in the AV room after classes.
Mr. Takahashi did?
高橋先生が？
Hikari said it was a lot of fun.
（悠子）
ひかりちゃん 言ってたよ
楽しかったって
He seems pretty spacey, but he's actually very caring.
ぼ〜っとしてるけど
あの先生 意外に面倒見いいよね
（ひまり）ふ〜ん
（悠子）何？
Hmm...
What?
Oh, nothing.
（ひまり）ううん 別に
To tell the truth, I still don't trust Mr. Takahashi!
（ひまり）
実をいうと
私は高橋先生をまだ信用していない
（高橋）
体だけだったから
うっかりガバッといっちまった
I got careless since it was just her body, and I hugged too hard.
町 気付いたかな？
I wonder if Machi noticed.
気付いてるよな 普通
Yeah, of course she did...
（ひまり）あっ！
（高橋）ん？
（高橋）おう
Hey.
Hello.
（ひまり）どうも
教師って
意外と早く帰っていいんですね
I didn't know teachers were allowed to leave so early.
Oh, yeah...
ああ まあ… ひまりちゃんは
わりと遅くまで残ってるんだな
And I see you stayed pretty late, Himari.
I did. I like the library.
（ひまり）
そうですね 図書室が好きで
Come to think of it, I hear you did amazingly well on the last exams.
（高橋）
そういえば ひまりちゃん
この前のテスト
すごかったみたいだな
Th-Thank you.
（ひまり）
あ… ありがとうございます
（高橋）
いつも 図書室で勉強を？
You always study in the library?
Y-Yes, and I read books to refresh myself.
（ひまり）
えっ ええ…
あとリフレッシュで本を読んだり
（高橋）
そうか
ひかりとは全然違うな
I see.
You're nothing like Hikari, huh?
That was suspicious.
（ひまり）
怪しい
He's always nice to my sister, but...
いつも お姉ちゃんに
よくしてくれてはいるけど…
ん？　どうした？
What's wrong?
N-Nothing...
いっ いいえ
Just worried that my sister's been bothering you.
姉が ご迷惑をおかけして
いるんじゃないかと
（高橋）
ハハッ 生物準備室で
涼ませてやってるだけだ
I've been letting her cool off in the biology prep room.
Is that right?
（ひまり）
どうだか 実は お姉ちゃんを
実験サンプルのように見てるんじゃ
Or are you actually looking at her as an experimental sample?
Oh, the experiment.
（高橋）ああ 実験…
（ひまり）えっ？
I forgot to prepare one for tomorrow's class.
（高橋）
明日の授業の準備忘れてた
器材 人数分 足りるかな？
I hope I'll have enough materials for everyone.
まあ 明日でいっか
Well, I can do it tomorrow.
I'm overthinking this...
（ひまり）
気にし過ぎね
デミ好きの先生でも
Even if he does love demis,
バンパイアの性質について
四六時中 考えているわけじゃ…
there's no way he thinks about the nature of vampires around the clock.
Oh, right!
（高橋）ああ そうだ
バンパイアの性質について
聞きたいんだけどさ
I wanted to ask you something about the nature of vampires.
（ひまり）
本当に考えてた！
He actually does!
Wh-What would that be?
なっ… 何でしょうか？
Hikari seems to have no problem chowing down on garlic,
ひかりはニンニクだろうと
むしゃむしゃ食べるみたいだが
よく聞く“バンパイアは
ニンニク嫌い”という伝承
but the stories you hear assume that vampires hate garlic.
あれは眉唾なのかどうか
考えてみたんだ
I was thinking about whether it was all fake.
R-Right...
（ひまり）はっ はあ…
（高橋）
バンパイアは夜
闇に紛れて 人を襲うという
They say vampires attack humans at night, under cover of darkness.
Why do you think that is?
なぜだと思う？
Uh, isn't it because they hate sunlight?
（ひまり）
ああ…
日光を嫌うからじゃないですか？
（高橋）
それだけで 十字架にすがるほど
恐れられはしないだろう
I don't think that makes them scary enough for people to carry crosses.
Some books say that vampires have very keen senses.
文献によっては バンパイアは
感覚が鋭いという記述もある
I think that's the reason.
俺は これが理由だと思う
昼夜を問わない視力
人を感知する聴力
Sharp vision, even at night, hearing that can detect humans,
血の臭いを嗅ぎ分ける嗅覚
a sharp sense of smell to pick up the scent of blood.
暗闇の中で
人より優位に立つには十分だ
That's more than enough for an advantage over humans in the dark.
What does the sharpness of their senses have to do with garlic?
五感の鋭さとニンニクに
何か関係が？
ああ ポイントは嗅覚の鋭さ
Well, the key point is their sense of smell.
鼻が効き過ぎるがゆえに
臭いの強い食べ物を嫌う
Since their noses are so sensitive, they hate strong-smelling foods.
I think that's why vampires in legends hate garlic.
それが“バンパイアは
ニンニクが嫌い”という
伝承の正体なのではないか
などと考察してみたんだが
I've been thinking about those things, but what's the real story?
どうだろうか？
ひかりは
五感が鋭かったりするのか？
Does Hikari have sharp senses?
Yes, that's quite accurate.
その認識で間違いないと思います
姉の五感は すごいです
My sister's senses are incredible.
（高橋）おっ やった〜
Oh! All right!
じゃあ ひかりは
なんで むしゃむしゃ ニンニクを？
Then, how can she eat so much garlic?
それは…
That's because...
She just isn't picky enough about her food.
姉が
好き嫌いがなさすぎるからです
不安になって確認したんです
I got concerned and asked her if she was forcing herself to eat it.
無理して
食べてるんじゃないかって
そしたら…
And she said...
It's fine, it's fine!
大丈夫 大丈夫
私 ニオイ きっついの好きだから
I love foods that smell really strong!
あ〜ん
ん〜！
う〜ん
お外で言ってほしくはないな
I wouldn't want her to say that in public.
はい 本当に
You can say that again...
Lots of people who talk to me about my sister say
この手の話になると
よく言われます
she doesn't seem like a vampire,
“姉はバンパイアらしくない”
that she's just like a normal high school girl.
“普通の女子学生と
変わらないじゃないか”と
高橋先生は デミの性質に
大層 ご執心のようですが
You seem very interested in demis' natures,
そのあたりは どうですか？
so what do you think of that?
Do you think my sister doesn't seem like a vampire?!
姉はバンパイアらしくないと
お思いですか？
Are you not that interested in her human side?
姉の人間性については
それほど
興味ありませんか？
Okay, I'll give you a straight answer.
そうだな ちゃんと言おう
確かに あいつはバンパイアの
性質に即した行動は あまりしない
It's true that she doesn't behave the way I'd expect a vampire to.
だが それで
But if you asked whether that makes her unlike a vampire,
バンパイアらしくないと言われると
それは違う
I'd say it doesn't.
Hikari does want to suck people's blood,
ひかりは
人から血を吸いたい気持ちはあるが
but she settles for blood bags.
パックで我慢している
And even though she has a vampire's keen sense of smell,
また バンパイアの鋭敏な嗅覚を
持ちながらなお
she loves foods with strong scents.
匂いの強い食べ物が好き
That human side is what makes her like a vampire,
そういった人間性が
あいつのバンパイアらしさであり
人間としての個性だ
and it's what makes her unique.
It isn't how you're born that makes you "like" something.
“らしさ”は
生まれ持った性質ではない
性質を踏まえて どう生きるかだ
It's how you live with what you are.
だからといって デミの性質の
理解を怠っていいわけじゃない
But that doesn't mean it's okay to ignore a demi's nature.
The concerns unique to demis are caused by their natures.
デミ特有の悩みは
必ず性質に起因するからだ
You can't look at things in only one way.
物の見方は 一方向ではダメだ
双方向でしかるべき
You should look from both angles.
デミの特性だけ見ていると
個性を見失う
If you just see traits unique to demis, you'll miss their individuality.
人間性だけ見ていると
悩みの原因に たどりつけない
If you only see the human side, you won't understand their troubles.
Both are precious.
どちらも大切だ
バランスが大事なんだ
What's important is balance.
That's what I think.
俺は そう考えている
（ひまり）
ぐうの音も出ない
I'm speechless.
信じてもいいかも
Maybe I can trust him...
Um, Mr. Takahashi...
あの 先生
うん？　何だ？
What's up?
Would you like to come to our house sometime?
（ひまり）
よかったら 今度
うちに来てもらえませんか？
（高橋）
おお こないだ行ったぞ
家の前までだけどな
Oh, I did, not long ago.
In front of it, anyway.
I'd like my parents to hear what you just said.
今の先生のお話
両親にも聞かせたくて…
（メールの受信音）
（高橋）そうか
Oh, okay!
実はな 俺も親御さんたちの話を
伺ってみたいとは思ってたんだ
Actually, I was thinking I'd like to talk to your parents, too.
（ひまり）先生…
（高橋）うん？
Mr. Takahashi...
Hmm?
By the way, I have a question for you!
（ひまり）
ちなみに質問なんですが！
What does hugging my sister let you learn?
ハグとは
姉の何を知るための行為ですか？
Mr. Takahashi hugged me today!
He totally attacked me!
バンパイアの性質ですか？
Was it her vampire nature, or her human side?!
姉の人間性ですか？
Hugged? Attacked?!
（高橋）
ハグされた？　襲われた？
何言ってたんだ あいつは
What is she thinking?
誤解だ ひまりちゃん
あいつから勝手に…
You've got it wrong, Himari! She's the one who—
（ひまり）
この 屁理屈(へりくつ)デミ好き教師〜！
You...
Rationalizing, demi-loving teacher!
I don't deny that, but still!
（高橋）それは 否定しないが〜！
（ひまり）お姉ちゃん！
Sis?
Sister, are you oka—
（ひまり）お姉ちゃん だいじょ…
（ひかり）おりゃ〜！
（ひまり）
で なんで
こんな誤解を生むメールを？
And why send me such a misleading message?
I'm sorry...
（ひかり）ごめんなさい…
You were so late getting home, and I was bored here.
ひまり 帰ってくるの遅いから
家で暇で
I thought if I sent a message like that, you'd come home faster.
そういうメール送ったら
早く帰ってきてくれるかなって
まさか 先生も一緒だったとは
I had no idea Mr. Takahashi was with you.
ハア〜
別に普通に 早く帰ってきてって
メールしてくれれば そうするから
If you'd just sent a message asking me to hurry home, I would have.
Really? I love you, Himari!
（ひかり）
本当？　ひまり 大好き！
（ひまり）抱きつかないでよ
Quit clinging to me!
♪〜
The events of a mysterious world,
Like the ones you hear of in fairy tales,
Are actually closer than you think
Just like the way you and I met!
When I stood up tall to gaze at
The familiar scenery outside my window,
Even days that felt like torture seemed precious somehow.
Stuck in my heart, I can't put them into words
How should I try to put these feelings into words?
Laughing over stupid things...
Getting mad over small details...
We'll keep carving these trivial moments into our hearts.
Sometimes I'm feeling sad...
But when I'm with you, I'm so happy!
We'll keep on building these irreplaceable moments,
And little by little, we'll come to understand one another.
〜♪
Next Time
The Little Snow Woman Is Cold
Next time on Interviews with Monster Girls:
（ひかり）
次回「亜人ちゃんは
語りたい」
The Little Snow Woman Is Cold.
「雪女ちゃんは冷たい」